Joshua Ringer

Software Engineer / Manager with 9 years' experience writing and designing web-based platforms, applications, and services.

Proficient in all aspects of software delivery: designing, coding, testing, deployment, server administration, support, and 3rd party service administration.

Proven leadership in running a team, managing multiple projects, and providing technological guidance across departments.

Skills

Code	Python	PHP	JavaScript	HTML	CSS (+ SASS, Stylu	sh sh	С
Build	pip	npm	Grunt	Gulp	Jenkins	CMake	
Deploy	AWS	Fabric	Vagrant	vSphere	httpd (Apache)	nginx	Docker
Manage	git	svn	hg	GitHub	GitLab	BitBucket	
Track	Redmine	Jira	Asana	Trello	Bugzilla		
Communicate	TCP/IP	HTTP	RTP	SIP	JSON	YAML	XML
Store	SQL (MySQL, Post	greSQL)	MongoDB	Redis			

Employment

May 2015-Apr 2017

Asia Genomics, SG

Senior Application Developer / Technical Project Manager

Joined company of <20, managed company IT (services such as Office365, Dropbox, network infrastructure), developed company website, e-commerce sites, and internal operational applications.

With company growth, oversaw purchase & deployment of equipment and infrastructure, as well as outsourcing of some development projects.

Hired and ran both the IT team and a 3-person development team; provided insight and guidance to business functions.

Apr 2013-Apr 2015

Cisco Systems, CA, USA

Senior Test Automation Engineer

Local test automation expert for a group of ~30 within the Collaboration Technologies Group producing the Virtual Telepresence Server and next-generation Telepresence Server products.

Responsible for developing, maintaining, running, and evaluating automated tests and the test environment, in collaboration with teams in the UK and Norway.

Contributed toward project test planning; provided guidance on automation activities.

 $Coached \ team \ members \ on \ automation \ and \ provided \ guidance \ on \ writing \ new \ test \ scripts \ and \ tool \ usage.$

Jul 2010-Apr 2013

Cisco Systems, UK

Test Tools Team Lead

Led a small team responsible for developing and maintaining test tools and services for a campus of ~200, providing test coverage for all telepresence infrastructure products developed by the group.

In charge of designing and providing direction for all of the team's projects, including various web services, a large distributed automation system, and a video endpoint simulator, all developed in-house.

Responsible for prioritising any user requests and issues, providing (or redirecting) any support required. Proud supplier of team beanbags, essential seating for productive and innovative team discussions.

Sep 2008–Jul 2010 Tandberg, UK Test Development Engineer

Developed and maintained the group's test automation framework, along with main test and result-tracking website, and provided support for both.

 $\label{thm:members} \mbox{Mentored other test team members in script-writing and use of the framework.}$

Education

Sep 2004–Sep 2008 University of Oxford, UK

MPhys, Physics

Achieved II:1 class degree, specialising in condensed matter, laser science, and quantum information processing.

Received a distinction in first-year exams, and was awarded a college scholarship.

Ultimate

What is Ultimate? youtu.be/KixMbFkrPIM

Current IT Director for Singapore's national association. Competed at World Beach Ultimate Championships 2017 for Singapore national team. Coaching a local club team.

Regular competitor at multiple tournaments around the world.

Committee member at University, built club website, formed Alumni team in 2008 to compete at inaugural alumni tournament in the UK.

Updated: Aug 2017